Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alivandenberg (LinkedIn) ankenylawyer.com/alexandria-vandenberg/ (Company)

Top Skills

Leadership Legal Writing Legal Research

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Legal Research Certification
Attorney
Professional Research Certification
Attorney

Honors-Awards

Nebraska Legends Scholar Drake Law Dean's List

Publications

Will Contests & The Perpetual State of Limbo: Why the Iowa Probate Code Needs to Evolve

Alexandria Vandenberg

Associate Attorney at Burnham Law Colorado Springs

Summary

Currently admitted to practice law in Iowa and Colorado.

I graduated from the University of Nebraska-Lincoln with my Bachelor's Degree in Political Science, and a minor in criminal justice. I then went on to graduate from Drake University Law School with High Honors.

During law school, I worked in the Children's Rights Clinic where I represented children in Child Abuse and Neglect cases. I participated in Law Review, Student Bar Association, was a member of the Client Counseling Team, and served as a Legal Writing Fellow.

After my Iowa Bar admission, and prior to relocating to Colorado, I worked at a general practice firm. My primary areas of focus were family law, juvenile law, real estate, and estate planning.

I have worked through complex family law matters, drafted wills and trusts, administered estates, represented parents and children in juvenile court, represented sellers and served as settlement agent in residential real estate transactions.

Experience

Burnham Law
Associate Attorney
September 2021 - Present (9 months)
Colorado Springs, Colorado, United States

Modern Family Law
Associate Attorney
January 2021 - August 2021 (8 months)

Burnham Law 5 months

Associate Attorney October 2020 - December 2020 (3 months)

Fort Collins, Colorado, United States

Law Clerk (Colorado License Pending) August 2020 - October 2020 (3 months) Fort Collins, Colorado, United States

Takekawa & Green, PLLC Associate Attorney September 2019 - August 2020 (1 year) Ankeny, IA

Maintained a general law practice including but not limited to:

Real estate: worked with both buyers and sellers, served as settlement agent, prepared ALTAs and other necessary closing documents, prepared purchase agreement and transfer documents.

Family law/juvenile law: represented clients through divorces, custody modifications, child support proceedings, and child in need of assistance cases.

Estate planning/probate: drafted wills, trusts, and powers of attorney; administered estates.

Landlord/tenant: represented both landlords and tenants in various disputes.

Takekawa & Green PLLC Law Clerk January 2019 - September 2019 (9 months) Ankeny, Iowa

Middleton Center for Children's Rights Student Attorney August 2018 - May 2019 (10 months) Des Moines, Iowa Area

 Represent abused and neglected children as their guardian-ad litem and attorney in Child In Need of Assistance proceedings.

- Represent incarcerated parents as their attorney in the Incarcerated Parents Project.
- Gather facts, draft legal documents, advocate for clients, and participate in court hearings in addition to attending weekly classes and case reviews.

Drake University Law School Legal Writing Fellow June 2017 - May 2019 (2 years)

As an extra resource for the Legal Writing professors, Legal Writing Fellows assist in various ways including but not limited to:

- Working one-on-one with Legal Writing students assisting in the legal writing process including legal memoranda and appellate briefs.
- Hosting legal writing workshops.
- Editing writing assignments prior to distribution to students.

Iowa Legal Aid Student Attorney/ Public Service Intern June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months) Des Moines, Iowa Area

Certified as a student attorney under Iowa Supreme Court rule 31.15(1), I provided legal advice and/or representation to low-income Iowans on various issues including but not limited to custody, child support, divorce, protective orders, and landlord/tenant issues.

Polk County District Court

Judicial Intern to the Honorable Robert B. Hanson

January 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)

Des Moines, Iowa

Interned with Judge Hanson who was assigned to a criminal felony trial docket. During my internship, I wrote legal memoranda, researched evidentiary issues, and observed a variety of court proceedings including multiple first-degree murder trials.

Simpson, Jensen, Abels, Fischer & Bouslog Law Clerk February 2017 - March 2018 (1 year 2 months) Des Moines, IA

 Prepared drafts of various transactional documents necessary for the formation of a limited liability company, including but not limited to: operating agreements, organizational minutes, and certificates of organization.

- Prepared legal memoranda by researching statutes, constitutions, regulations, court opinions, and secondary sources pertaining to various types of law, including but not limited to, business & corporate law, employment & labor law, personal injury & wrongful death, litigation, and real estate law.
- Updated Corporate minute books to ensure accuracy and compliance with the law.
- Requested, collected and organized medical records, billing records, and insurance liens.
- Observed attorney-client meetings.
- Filtered phone calls requesting legal representation.

Anderson Creager & Wittstruck Legal Runner August 2015 - July 2016 (1 year)

Lincoln, Nebraska

- Filed legal documents with the state and federal courts.
- Filed business documents with the Secretary of State.
- · Compiled discovery requests.
- Delivered and picked up documents.
- · Assist with office efficiency.

State of Nebraska Legislative Page January 2016 - April 2016 (4 months) Lincoln, NE

- While working in the Nebraska Unicameral Legislature during the 104th Legislature, 2nd Session, I gained both a political and legal perspective of the unique Nebraska state law making process.
- Responded to senators' requests for assistance on the legislative floor.
- Answered incoming calls to the legislative chamber.
- Prepared for and assisted with committee hearings.

Education

Drake University Law School Juris Doctorate (J.D.) · (2016 - 2019)

University of Nebraska-Lincoln
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Political Science/ Criminal Justice · (2014 - 2016)

Activity

05/31/2022, Viewed by Dale Capelouto

05/31/2022, Lawrence Allen added candidate to Old Republic Title - Real Estate Attorney